お前を殺す者がいるとすれば
If anyone kills you,
it will be either the Demon King…
それは魔王か…
or a human mage.
人間の魔法使いだ
You're there like the wind
Closing your eyes at sunset
I wonder what's on your mind
Beyond Journey's End
With your eyelids open
Your eyes shone like glass
It faintly smelled like a sunny day
Clear up the sky, let flowers bloom
Bloom and blame it on the sunny sky
Even the rain, when it stops
Will make you shine in the sunlight
Calm the stirring sounds in my heart
We go like the sunny wind
Go on and fly over that cloud
Further and further away
Episode 26: The Height of Magic
防がれた。
It blocked it.
想定の範囲内だね。
We expected this much.
From here on out,
it's a battle of attrition.
ここから先は消耗戦だ。
本当にいたな
メトーデの観測結果の通りだ。
They really are here.
Methode's observations were correct.
Try not to hold me back.
足を引っ張るなよ。
こっちのセリフだ。
I could say the same thing.
メトーデが複製体の
正確な位置を割り出した
Methode has determined the
exact locations of the enemy.
混戦になると勝ち目はない
We can't beat them in a
disorganized free-for-all.
複製体が
ここに集結する前に
So we'll split up and stop the replicas
before they gather here.
分散して足止めを図るぞ
苦手な相手を
教え合っただろう
We told each other our weakest matchups.
自分にとって苦手な相手は
複製体にとっても苦手な相手だ
Your own weakest matchup
is your replica's as well.
話し合い　連携できることが
儂らの利点だ
Our advantage is that we can
communicate and work together.
戦う相手を正しく選択すれば
As long as we choose the right opponents,
こちらは幾分か有利に戦える
we'll have the upper hand.
１人で勝てん相手には
数で対処しろ
Use numbers to deal with anyone
we can't fight alone.
It's funny how easy this is.
面白いほど楽に戦える
これなら
複製体たちを抑えられる
If we do this, we can stop the replicas.
じゃあ　作戦通りに
Follow the plan.
ああ　健闘を祈る
Got it. Good luck.
There's one concern.
懸念が１つ
探知できている
複製体の総数が
I'm detecting fewer replicas than test-takers.
受験者よりも
わずかに少ないです
In particular, I can't find
Ms. Sense's replica, the greatest threat.
特に　一番の脅威である
ゼンゼさんの複製体の反応が
見つかりません
確かに感知できないね
You're right. I don't detect it either.
ゼンゼの複製体は
さすがに看過できない
We mustn't overlook Sense's replica.
挟撃される形になったら
フェルンを守り切れないし
If she comes at us from behind,
I won't be able to protect Fern.
最悪　２人とも死ぬかも
Worst case, we could both die.
フェルンさんと
デンケンさんの
I haven't found Ms. Fern or
Mr. Denken's replicas either.
複製体の位置も
把握できていませんし
精度の高い近距離探知で
探すしかありませんね
We'll have to search for them using
more precise close-range detection.
お前が　この場にいなければ
We wouldn't have had to worry
about this if you weren't here.
こんな懸念も
いらなかったんだがな
一級魔法使いは
理不尽なほどの逆境でも
First-class mages must be able
to overcome unfair adversity.
覆せるような
存在でなければならない
この程度は逆境ですらない
And this doesn't even qualify as adversity.
それに仲間の背中を守るだけで
合格できるんだ
Besides, you can pass the test by simply
watching your fellow test-takers' backs.
実に優しい　平和な試験だ
Is this not a truly kind and peaceful test?
倒した…
でも　いい気分じゃねえな。
It's down,
but I can't say I enjoyed that.
奇襲…！
An ambush.
うっ！
化け物が…。
Damned monstrosity.
魔力探知を怠った覚えは
ないんだがな。
I don't recall neglecting
my mana detection.
ラヴィーネ　お前も瓶を割れ。
Lawine, you should break your bottle, too.
くっ…。
引き際が分からないほど
ガキじゃないだろう。
You're old enough to know when to quit.
試験は３年後もある。
The test will be held again in three years.
クソ…！
Damn it.
間に合わなかったか…
I didn't make it in time.
だが　儂が加勢したところで
But my help wouldn't
have changed the outcome.
結果は同じだっただろう
背中を向けているというのに
Even with its back turned,
I still don't detect any openings.
まるで隙を感じん
どちらにせよ
時間稼ぎぐらいはせんとな
Either way, I must at least buy some time.
確か宮廷魔法使いの
デンケンだっけ？
You're Denken the Imperial Mage, right?
今　どういう状況なの？
What's going on here?
もしかして　あれと戦うつもり？
Are you planning to fight that thing?
勝てないと思うよ。
I don't think you can beat it.
I know.
承知の上だ。
ねぇ　デンケン。
Denken, do we have to do this
to conquer the dungeon?
これって　迷宮攻略に
必要なことなの？
今　フリーレンが…。
Frieren is currently—
I didn't ask for an explanation.
Is this necessary?
説明はいい　必要なことなの？
そうだ。
Yes.
なら　私が倒すよ。
Then I'll defeat it.
何を言っているんだ。
What are you talking about?
Denken is the strongest one here.
この中で一番強いのはデンケンだ。
第一　お前はヴィアベルにも
勝てなかっただろう。
You couldn't even beat Wirbel.
ん～…
そういうことじゃないんだよね。
Yeah, that's not how this works.
It's true that I'm an inexperienced
third-class mage.
確かに私は未熟な三級魔法使いだ。
デンケンやヴィアベルよりも
はるかに弱い。
I'm far weaker than Denken or Wirbel.
けれども
ゼンゼ相手なら勝てると思うよ。
But I think I can beat Sense.
私の得意魔法は　これ。
This is my specialty.
Reelseiden, a spell that
cuts almost anything.
「大体なんでも切る魔法」
大体なんでも切る魔法。
私が切れると思ったものは
何でも切れるし
It cuts anything I think it can,
and it can't cut anything I think it can't.
切れないと思ったものは
全く切れない。
So what? That spell is easily
blocked by defensive magic.
それが何だっていうんだ。
防御魔法で簡単に防げる魔法だ。
そういえば　メガネ君は
Oh, right. You watched my battle
against Wirbel, didn't you, four-eyes?
ヴィアベルとの戦いを
見ていたんだっけ？
まぁ　防御魔法って
魔法を防ぐためのものだからね。
Yeah, defensive magic is for blocking spells.
切れるイメージ
あんまりないんだよね。
It's hard for me to imagine cutting it.
そうか　なら　どちらにせよ
ゼンゼには通用しない。
I see. Then either way,
it won't work against Sense.
あの髪には　観測できるだけでも
Based only on what we can observe,
防御魔法に匹敵するほどの魔法が
何重にもかけられている。
that hair has multiple layers of spells
equal to defensive magic cast on it.
だから　そんな理屈は
どうでもいいんだよ。
I told you, that sort of logic doesn't matter.
これはイメージの話なんだから。
I'm talking about what I can visualize.
おい　待て。
Hey, wait.
う～ん。
Huh.
Figures. Sorganeil doesn't work.
やっぱり　見た者を拘束する魔法は
効かないか。
まぁ
髪ってのは体の一部だからね。
Well, a person's hair is part of their body.
全身を視界に納めるのは無理だ。
It's impossible to see all of her at once.
大体なんでも切る魔法。
Reelseiden.
As I thought, Übel is fighting my replica.
やはり　私の複製体の
相手はユーベルか
勝敗は　すでに分かっている
I already know who will win.
恐らく戦いにすらならない
It won't even be a real fight.
It happened two years ago,
during the second-class mage exam.
あれは２年前の
二級魔法使い選抜試験だった。
その第二次試験の
試験官を担当したのは
Burg, a first-class mage,
proctored the second test.
ブルグ一級魔法使い。
彼は一級魔法使いになってから
He was so skilled in defensive magic
一度たりとも
手傷を負ったことがないほどの
that he hadn't been injured once
since becoming a first-class mage.
守りに特化した魔法使いだった。
「不動の外套」。
“Immovable Cloak.”
The cloak he created using mana
彼が魔法で作り出す外套は
was imbued with so many defensive spells
that no magical attack could penetrate it.
あらゆる攻撃魔法も
通さないほどの防御術式が
組み込まれていた。
第二次試験の内容は
For the second test, the test-takers fired
offensive magic against Burg and his cloak.
外套をまとったブルグに
受験者が攻撃魔法を放ち
１歩でも下がらせたら合格という
極めて単純なものだった。
It was a simple test. If they could make him
take just one step back, they passed.
殺害行為を失格とする
ルールも
Killing would result in disqualification,
攻撃魔法の最低限の制御を促し
and limits were imposed on offensive
magic to protect the other test-takers.
他の受験者を守るための
措置だった。
次
Next.
誰もブルグの心配など
していなかった。
No one was worried about Burg.
あ～…　切り過ぎちゃった
Oh, I cut too deep.
ざわめき
それを
三級魔法使いになったばかりの
But he was easily killed
by a no-name girl who'd just recently
become a third-class mage.
無名の少女が
あっさりと殺してしまった。
失格処分だって話だよね
This means I fail, right?
分かってるから
もう帰っていい？
I get it. Can I leave now?
１つだけ質問がある
I have just one question for you.
ど～ぞ
Go ahead.
How did you defeat his Immovable Cloak?
「不動の外套」を
どうやって打ち破った？
え～っと
Have you ever sewn before, Sense?
ゼンゼさんって
裁縫とかしたことある？
いいや　それがどうした？
No. Why do you ask?
家柄　良さそうだもんね～
You do seem like you come
from a rich family.
Or do you use magic to handle all that stuff?
それとも　そういうのは
魔法で全部やっちゃうのかな？
いやね　私も不器用だから
I've actually never tried it myself,
since I'm so clumsy.
そういうことは
したことないんだけど
姉貴がよく
裁縫をしているのを見ていた
But I used to watch my sister
sew all the time.
布を裁断する時ってさ
When you cut cloth, you place the scissors
against it like this and slide them through.
ハサミをこう入れて
シャ～って切るんだよね
とてもいい音がするんだ
It makes a really nice sound.
私は　あの音が好きだった
I liked that sound.
話が見えない
I don't see where you're going with this.
I'm talking about visual imagination.
イメージの話だよ
布っていうのはさ
切れるものなんだよ
Cloth can be cut.
You expect to be able to cut it.
切れて当たり前のものだ
こいつはイカれている
She's out of her mind.
確かに布を切るイメージなんて
誰でもできる
It's true that anyone can
imagine cutting cloth.
バカにだってできる
Even an idiot can do that.
だが　魔法の世界は
そんなに甘いものじゃ　ない
But the world of magic isn't so simple.
完璧にイメージできないものは
魔法では実現できない
Magic can't create anything
the caster can't visualize perfectly,
小さなアリが巨大な竜を
just as a diminutive ant can't imagine
crushing a colossal dragon underfoot.
踏みつぶすイメージが
できないように
Hardly any mages can imagine
penetrating that cloak
鉄壁の防御術式で守られた
あの外套を
切るイメージができる
魔法使いなど　ほぼ存在しない
and its impregnable magical defenses.
実際に　あの外套が
Any mage can tell at a glance that
that cloak blocks all magical attacks.
いかなる攻撃魔法も
通さないことは
魔法使いなら
一目見れば分かるからだ
Truly, any idiot can see that.
それこそ　バカでも分かる
人が知性を持った
生命体である限り
As long as people are intelligent organisms,
we cannot escape those fetters.
その柵からは
決して逃れられない
それでも彼女は
自らの感覚に従った
But she trusted her own intuition instead.
「これは切れないものだ」と
知性では分かっていながら
Despite understanding intellectually
that it couldn't be cut,
感覚のままに「不動の外套」を
切り裂くイメージを構築した
she constructed a vision of cutting
through the cloak according to her intuition.
もはや　人として成立している
精神状態とは思えない
Her mind must not function like a person's.
これは才覚の領域だ
It's practically a superpower.
もう行っていいかな？
ああ
Can I go now?
Yes.
ところでゼンゼさん
キレイな髪の毛だね
By the way, Sense, that's some pretty hair.
手入れとか大変でしょ？
It must be tough to maintain.
もしかしたら
私は　あの時点で
Perhaps I had already lost to her then.
もう負けていたのかもしれない
ユーベルには
勝てるイメージが湧かない
I can't imagine beating Übel.
相性が悪過ぎる
She's that bad a matchup for me.
You all think too hard.
Hair is something to be cut.
みんな　頭を使い過ぎなんだよ。
髪は切るものでしょ？
髪の手入れ？
Maintaining my hair?
地獄だよ
It's hell.
考えたくもない
I don't even want to think about it.
フフっ。
Then you should cut it.
切ったらいいのに。
話は大体分かったぜ。
I've got the picture.
お前らはフリーレンが
水鏡の悪魔を倒すまでの
So you're buying time until
Frieren defeats the Spiegel.
時間稼ぎをしているわけだ。
はい　そうです。
Yes, that's right.
複製体なら
俺たちも３体　片付けた。
We defeated three of the replicas.
なら　話は早いですね。
That will make things easier.
それでは…。
In that case… Oh, my.
あら。
たった今　ゼンゼさんの複製体が
撃破されたようです。
Ms. Sense's replica was just destroyed.
この魔力…。
This mana…
仕留めたのは
ユーベル三級魔法使いですね。
It was the third-class mage Übel
who defeated it.
意外な結果だな。
That's surprising.
そうか？　結構　相性悪めだろ。
Is it? She was a pretty bad matchup for it.
魔法使い同士の戦いは
Battles between mages
are like rock-paper-scissors.
ジャンケンのようなもの
ですからね。
ただし　手数が無数にあり
However, it is a complex and difficult game
of rock-paper-scissors with infinite options.
極めて複雑で難解な
ジャンケンです。
それで　少しでも
使える手数を
And you want as many options as possible, huh?
増やしたいってわけか。
いいぜ　複製体の足止め
手伝ってやるよ。
Sure. We'll help you slow down the replicas.
俺は他人を信じるような
タチじゃねえが
I don't make a habit of trusting others,
ケツを振っている勝ち馬を
逃すほどバカじゃ　ない。
but I'm not dumb enough to let a winning
horse go when it's right in front of me.
現時点で確実に
足止めしなければならない
Currently, there are two
dangerous replicas we must stop.
危険な複製体は２体。
そのうちの１体
I've determined the location of
one of them: Mr. Denken's replica.
デンケンさんの複製体の
場所は特定しました。
あなた方は
そちらをお願いします。
I'd like you to handle that one.
もう１体のフェルンさんの
複製体に関しては
Allow me to handle the other:
Ms. Fern's replica.
私に任せてください。
She's particularly skilled
at concealing her mana.
あの子は特に魔力を消すのが
上手みたいですから
さすがに見つけ出さないと
奇襲で死者が出かねません。
Unless we find her replica,
it could ambush and kill someone.
Can you really handle it alone?
本当に１人で何とかなるの？
１人の方が
魔力探知に集中できます。
Working alone will allow me to
focus better on mana detection.
あの子　結構強いわよ。
She's pretty strong, you know.
私は多才なので
足止めだけは得意なのです。
I have many talents.
When it comes to simply stopping
someone, I'm quite skilled.
それに
拘束魔法が通じることは
Besides, I confirmed with the actual Ms. Fern
that my binding magic would work on her.
Take this.
本人の体を使って
確かめましたから。
I can't move.
よし。
All right. Let's go fight this thing.
じゃあ　一暴れするか。
ユーベル　これってさ
Übel, I'm not imagining this, am I?
僕の見間違いじゃないよね。
だろうね。
Probably not.
だって　メガネ君　動けないでしょ。
After all, you can't move, can you?
私の複製体が復活している。
My replica is back in action.
これって　もしかして
Will this keep going until
that Spiegel thing is defeated?
水鏡の悪魔とやらを倒すまで
続くのかな？
消耗戦だ　楽しくなってきたね。
It's a battle of attrition.
This is getting fun.
まったくだ。
I couldn't agree more.
もう引き際でしょ　これ。
Isn't it time for us to get out of here?
この隙もダメだな
This opening won't do either.
今のフェルンじゃ
気が付けない
Fern wouldn't notice it.
やっぱり　やるしかない
I'll have to do it after all.
The vulnerability in my mana detection
isn't enough to kill me.
魔力探知の隙だけじゃ
殺し切れるほどのものには
ならないね
You're right.
そうですね…
もっと大きな隙があれば
勝てるのですが…
We could win with a bigger opening, though.
勝てるんだね
You can win, right?
Then I'll create an opening.
なら　隙をつくろう
そんなことが
できるのですか？
Is that possible?
私が隙を見せれば
If I show an opening, then the replica
will show an even greater one.
相手は　もっと大きな隙を見せる
But that would mean you…
それでは　フリーレン様が…
防御に集中すれば
If I focus on defense, it won't be fatal.
致命傷にはならない
では　その場合の作戦は…
Then what strategy should we use?
任せるよ
It's up to you. If you think
we can win, then we can.
フェルンが勝てると
思っているのなら勝てる
なぜ
そう言い切れるのですか？
How can you be so sure?
だって　「私」は
Because I underestimate you.
フェルンのことを
なめているから
I'm glad to hear that.
それはよかったです
That means we have a decent shot at winning.
なら　十分勝機はありますね
まだ立っている
It's still standing, but that's a fatal wound.
でも　致命傷だ
とどめを…
I should finish it—
あ！
何が起こった…
What happened? Was I attacked?
攻撃された？
魔力を全く感じない…
I don't sense any mana.
この攻撃を　私は魔法として
認識できていない…
I'm not recognizing this attack as a spell.
Incredible, Ms. Frieren.
すごいです…　フリーレン様…。
So this is the height of magic.
これが魔法の高みなんですね…。
でも　らしくないです…。
But this isn't like you.
隙だらけです。
You've left yourself wide open.
Well done, Fern.
よくやった　フェルン。
あれを見せるほど
追い詰められたのは
It's been about eighty years
since I was last forced to use that.
８０年ぶりかな。
それじゃあ
さっさと終わらせようか。
Now, let's end this.
終わりましたか…。
So it's over.
もう動けない…。
I can't move another millimeter.
ヴィアベル…　おんぶしてくれ…。
Wirbel, carry me.
お前ら　いつも倒れてんな…。
You guys just can't stay on your feet, huh?
ここが零落の王墓の
最深部か…。
So this is the bottom of the
Ruins of the King's Tomb.
君たちは零落の王墓を攻略した。
You've conquered the
Ruins of the King's Tomb.
一級魔法使いに十分匹敵する
Such a notable achievement makes you
worthy of becoming first-class mages.
歴史に名を残すほどの偉業だ。
約束通り
最深部にたどり着いた全員を
As promised, everyone who made it here
has passed the second test.
第二次試験　合格とする。
それで　一番の功労者は
どこに行った？
So, where are the ladies of the hour?
暗いよ～‼
It's dark and scary in here!
怖いよ～‼
あ～　暗いよ　怖いよ～。
えぇ…。
It's dark! It's scary!
まぁ　気持ちは分かるかな。
I guess I understand that feeling.
Dark! Scary!
ふぅ…。
それでは
第二次試験を終了とする。
The second test is now over.
なんと
回復魔法まで使えるのじゃ。
It can even use healing magic.
どうじゃ　すごいじゃろう。
Impressive, right?
ああ…。
Uh, yeah.
誰なの？　お前。
Who are you?
And I'm alright (I'll be alright)
Yeah, I hear you (I care about you)
The wind teases this hair that's longer now
There's meaning in everything
Even the days that came to a halt
Now that I finally understand,
I've caught up to you
See, things that couldn't have been
Seen if it weren't for these eyes
Why? They begin to overflow
I won't ask to see you, so at least
Let me remember the past, just for today
So, if we were to meet again
No more hesitations, I'd choose the present
Anytime, anywhere, yah (wherever you are)
Anytime, anywhere (smile for me)
I'll be there (close your eyes,
and I'll always be there)
Even if there are no absolutes
I'm always aware of your thoughts
Those tears will be alright,
dawn will surely break
I'm whispering our lullaby
for you to come back home
It's been with me ever since I was little.
You were unlucky this time.
That's the spell Flamme taught you.
I may seem fine, but I'm actually
in a terrible mood right now.
You're in really rough shape.
The third test will now begin.
Fern, let's head back.
Just make fun of me like you always do.
Episode 27
An Era of Humans
The era of humans has arrived.